{
    "id": "b66a19b949874cbe89209b742f30f14a",
    "title": "Gerund vs. Infinitive",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I hate …………………………… to wait for people who are always late.",
            "description": "Either the infinitive or the gerund is possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "to have",
                "having"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Could you tell me why you delayed ………………………….. the money?",
            "description": "Delay is usually followed by an ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "to send",
                "sending",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor asked him to give up …………………………",
            "description": "Give up is usually followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to smoke",
                "smoke",
                "smoking"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I encouraged her ………………………… again.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to try",
                "trying",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They told us …………………………..",
            "description": "Tell is followed by a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "stopping",
                "to stop",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I dislike people ……………………….. me what to do.",
            "description": "Dislike is usually followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to tell",
                "telling",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I felt like …………………………. but I didn’t dare to.",
            "description": "Feel like is usually followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to laugh",
                "laughing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t help …………………………. his courage.",
            "description": "Can't help is followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to admire",
                "admiring",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We can’t risk …………………………. any more lives.",
            "description": "Risk is usually followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to lose",
                "losing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I tried to stop him from …………………………..",
            "description": "Stop is followed by from + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to leave",
                "leaving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We could not restrain him from …………………………..",
            "description": "Restrain is followed by object + from + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to move",
                "moving"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My parents always motivated me .................................. big.",
            "description": "Motivate is followed by an infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "dreaming",
                "to dream",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}